Thank you for watching!
Check the members' academic ability in six subjects: major subjects at the junior high school level and general entertainment common sense questions.
The member with the lowest total score will be the 4th brain king!
This time, from Mika's Goto
It's out.
Let's go to Miki's answer!
Aaaaah!
I'm standing, I'm standing.
I'm standing up.
It's standing.
Like a candle.
Oh, my God.
Like a happy heart.
Like a candle.
Happy birthday.
I think it's his birthday.
What's this?
What are you doing with the batteries?
I've only ever changed the battery.
That's what most people do, isn't it?
We all do.
I used to put them vertically.
I don't put them vertically.
No, no, no.
I don't know what time the batteries were used.
Put them vertically
That's what I thought.
You already thought this would work.
It's interesting that you put it up.
This is interesting.
It looks like a candle.
Let's continue...
Next...
Here is a social problem.
Social Problems
It's hard to bet on the full name, isn't it?
Here is the correct answer.
Fumio Kishida
Fumio Kishida-san, sir.
Fumio Kishida, right?
Let's go to Iki's answer.
Huh?
I know his face. It's Kishida-san.
Kishida. Get in.
I wonder...
That's his first name.
I couldn't even think of Kishida-san at first.
I wrote it down to tell you that I know who he is.
I wrote it to let you know who it was.
Then about a minute before the end, I had an epiphany.
But I still can't come up with the first name.
That's not easy.
Endo. Let's go with Endo.
That's too bad.
It's just what you'd expect, right?
That's a big one.
It's not a letter.
It was there, but...
The ground floated over and over like this.
Inoue.
What?
Daisuke Kishi
Daisuke Kishi.
Do you mind if I take a picture?
Yes, sir.
What?
The one with the diamonds.
There's a character played by Yusuke.
This is Mr. Uzuma's name. He's a famous actor.
I've seen it before. Me too.
Inoue, did you write this?
I've seen something about it.
He's the Prime Minister of Japan. Here.
Daisuke Kishi.
How did you get this?
The Prime Minister of Japan.
In a topknot.
It's funny.
Let's move on to the next problem.
Oh, this is hard!
This one is really hard!
This is a new banknote to be issued from this year.
It's a new person.
What?
That's right.
You're lying.
This year.
No, you don't know that either?
The money changes?
The money changes. The people who write about it...
It will change this year.
Oh, I thought they were from the past.
No, these are people from the past.
You wrote in the question, "The new banknotes to be issued this year".
I was hoping you could figure out the correct answer from the hints in the kanji used in the name.
I was hoping you could help me figure out the correct answer.
Each person got 5 in a row.
Kubo's solution
First of all, yikes!
Eiichi Shibusawa, what's his name?
Sawamura Kazuki
What?
Why?
Sawamura Kazuki, it's not a question.
What do you mean, what's this?
There is a possibility that it will be from now on.
Let's go to Ogawa's answer.
Oh, he's a cat.
Umekichi Tadashi.
Ogawa.
Um, she's a woman.
First of all
What is it, Yoshimasa?
Yoshimasa, a man from the past.
I've heard of him quite often.
Because I hear it so often...
I thought it might apply to you.
You like Yoshimasa, don't you?
It sounds like Yoshimasa Tokugawa.
I like him. Come on, Mukai.
Mukai.
Mitsuharu Misawa.
Mitsuharu Misawa
Mitsuharu Misawa, he's a professional wrestler.
The second Tiger Mask.
How do you know all the kanji?
I only know Umeko Tsuda's.
When I erased Ume, only Yama and Sawa remained.
Look at that.
Misawa was left.
Why use it all on one person?
But you knew Mitsuharu from Misawa.
I liked wrestling.
That's all that came up.
It's great to see Misawa.
And the next one is great.
Tamura.
Tamura?
Yes, sir.
What?
What? That's great.
You guessed it.
I wrote all the names in kanji.
Wait a minute.
The question about Prime Minister Kishida earlier.
Can I see Tamura's answer?
Prime Minister Kishida's question.
Why did he write his full name in kanji?
It's true.
Tamura...
I'll be suspected of cheating.
I'll need a full explanation.
Please wait!
I've been meaning to ask you.
Let me tell you one thing.
There's a reason why you can't cheat.
I was alone with Okayo when I took the test.
So I can't see his answers.
I can't.
Tamura, why do you love money so much?
No...
Why is money such a big deal?
I was just talking to my family recently.
It just so happens.
That's how I remembered it.
That's great.
That's what I'm talking about.
Okay, well, here's the next question.
Inbound.
You hear it all the time in the news.
Make a correct sentence using the word "inbound".
You understand, don't you, Mr. Himura?
Yes, I do.
In short, foreign tourists come to Japan.
Inbound consumption.
I want you to make a correct sentence.
I want you to make sentences that include inbound consumption.
Oh, you want me to make a sentence?
Lilia's answer
Lilia.
Something about the ball going inbounds.
We lost, didn't we?
We lost.
What's this?
What's the game?
Inbound register...
What an irregular... irregular bounce!
When I heard "bounce", I thought it was a ball.
You know, like in basketball, there's a rebound.
I lost because it bounced inside like that.
Inbounds inside...
Like an own-goal
Answer of intention
Hey, they said inbound is a foul.
What the hell?
I'm not talking to anyone.
He said inbound is a foul.
So they've been doing it all this time.
Yeah, I guess we did.
You did it, inbound.
That's funny.
Interesting.
Let's hear Dr. Yumiki's answer.
You have a lot of teachers this time.
Oh, me?
I'm inbound again.
Why are you acting like such a jerk?
Why?
I'm inbound again.
I don't like it.
Here is Dr. Nakamura's answer
Yakiniku is twice as good when inbound to rice
Is that called inbound?
It's called "one-ban", isn't it?
Is that inbound?
Is that what you mean by inbound?
I didn't know it was called "inbound".
That's great, Dr. Nakamura!
This is really good!
I really want to give you a pass!
Answer of Promi
Promo
I have to get two receipts due to the inbound system.
Wow, wow, wow, wow.
I don't have one.
I actually said this answer pretty well.
I mistook it for an invoice.
That's what you meant.
I was so confident.
That's why everyone thinks they're right, but they're wrong.
Next, let's look at this one.
The Black Ships' arrival in Japan
Explain in detail using only the necessary words from the following.
In short, there are a lot of dummy words in this question.
So, please use only the words that explain the arrival of the black ships.
I see.
The Going Merry... that's the ship Luffy was on.
I see...
First, Kaki's answer.
Correct.
I see.
Perry came to Japan on a black ship to open the country to the outside world.
If you've written this much, you've already answered correctly.
Good, good, good.
That's why Perry's the only one who uses them.
Perry's the only one.
Don't you need more?
We're all very anxious about this.
I'm okay with just Perry.
Yes, sir.
Tsutsui's explanation.
Perry came to Japan on the Going Merry.
I told you earlier.
I said it earlier. Tsutsui
The Going Merry is a ship that appears in One Piece.
Perry didn't come on board.
What kind of reaction is that?
I've never read a single volume of the manga in my life.
I've never read a single volume of the manga.
I thought he must have really come on board
Then why did you use this?
I shouldn't have used it.
Ume's answer.
Oops.
MacArthur came aboard the Going Merry with guns.
Ume, recently!
Ume, what a mess!
Well, I just took what I thought was necessary.
I didn't understand this part either.
It's all gibberish?
No, I understand. I know about the Black Ships.
No, you don't.
The Going Merry.
Yes, I know.
Your answer.
Why did you all think you'd be invited?
I'm confident.
Yes, I am.
Xavier came over from Peru with Perry.
The sword hunting system allowed foreigners to use guns in Japan.
I used a lot.
I used it a lot.
And yet...
First, Xavier comes from Peru on a penny.
He's getting on a penny.
What penny did you get on?
I thought it was a ride called a penny.
I thought I'd better spend a lot of pennies.
I'm still confused by the fact that it's a penny ride.
But I could tell that Going Merry Go was different.
It's interesting, isn't it?
Interesting.
Now the next question.
Yes.
That's great.
Now we have three swords.
Mr. Himura, what do you think this is simply a ranking?
Let's see...
"How big they are.
Correct.
The large area of Hokkaido is a hint.
The presence of Hokkaido gives us a clue.
Here it is.
Endo's answer.
The ranking of the best seafood.
That's true.
I understand.
It certainly may not be a hassle
Especially delicious!
I don't eat seafood when I come to Hokkaido.
That's up to the individual.
What's this?
Seafood is the only thing I can think of when I think of Hokkaido.
It's delicious.
But then again, I think Aomori.
I don't know.
Akita's got great souvenirs, too.
Interesting
Okamoto's answer.
Yes.
Ranking the best rice
Ranking of the best fish caught in Japan
I'm deleting this one, actually I'm deleting it.
Ranking of places that take a long time to get to
There's a lip on this one.
Well, that's true, but...
No, I don't know where to start.
I don't know where to start.
Tokyo.
I'm moving on.
Well, it's gonna take me a while to get there.
It does.
But then, Okinawa's a long way away.
There's no place to start.
Let's go to Iwamoto.
It's snowing.
I don't know if that's the way to say it.
It's nice.
If it was snowing, it would be the other way around.
That's right.
Maybe you want to say "snow"?
It's going to be snowy.
That's why it's written in gal.
It's snowing!
Okaidoh and Iwate got snowed in the moment they arrived in Fukushima.
No, it's fine.
It's snowing!
The fish in the waterfall... Giant...
Now we come to the problem of finding English sentences that match the situation in the illustration.
For example, "The phone is ringing." "Whose phone is this?
If the conversation between the two is precise, it's a good answer.
Sameer
Of course, Seimia can speak English.
But I'd like you to take a look at this.
Can you read this? Sameer.
Hey, can I see your phone just in case you're having a relationship with somebody else?
Sameer, what's this saying?
Can I see your phone just in case you're having a relationship with somebody else?
Oh, my God.
You're going to get me there.
Don't go there.
Just in case.
Can I take a look at it just in case you're doing something with someone other than me?
You're scaring me.
You're right, of course, but this is scary.
Don't look.
It's scary that you're saying this from this picture.
Next, another illustration question.
If it's the last line a shopkeeper would say, it's the correct answer.
Tamura's
What?
No.
Here you are
Thank you
Good bye.
What?
Good bye
Good bye.
Good bye is right.
That's right.
BYE
Bay is like a one or an illie or something.
Good bye.
You're talking out of your ass.
What do you mean, "buy"?
Bye.
It's not the same as a bai.
Buy is a BUI.
That's right.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
what's buy?
what is it?
It's different.
It's different if you persist.
It's different!
Sakaguchi's Answer
Here you are, thank you. I'm a tomato.
Tomato? Huh? I'm a tomato?
That's because the balloon comes from a tomato.
That's right.
Am I right? This one.
Is that...
Is that right?
This is incorrect.
Because tomatoes don't talk.
I'm not talking about some fantasy.
Why can't I say tomatoes?
I'm just wondering why there's a speech bubble here.
Because it looks like it's coming from a tomato.
That's great.
Next, a question about translating English sentences into Japanese.
Nimura and Kaede Sato appear, but what is the correct answer?
Himura is mad because...
Kaede gives him a drop on his leg.
Scissors.
Scissors is scissors.
Because she drops scissors on his leg.
That's dangerous.
You'll get angry, won't you?
I'm going to get angry, no matter how much Kaede says.
Of course not.
Yes, it is.
If you're not careful, you'll kill someone someday.
Drop something.
Iwamoto's turn.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Himura is hungry.
So he eats candy.
Drop.
Not "drop", "candy".
Angry, too. For some reason, I thought it was Angry.
Because it's Himura.
Then I thought it was Neplage's candy.
Maple, right? Maple symbol.
Nepraj's.
That's why I thought he wanted to eat candy.
Lilia.
Himura is angry
Because Kaede spilled sushi on his lap.
Where's the sushi going?
where's the sushi?
S something like...
Scissors.
That's what I thought sushi was.
I thought it must be food, because I have an image of spilling the phone
I looked for food.
I thought maybe he spilled sushi.
I see.
Now, here's the explanation from the person himself, Kaede Sato.
Yes.
Mr. Himura got angry because the ocean dropped a shisa in his lap.
Shisa's a pain in the ass. Ittey, don't drop them in the ocean.
A big shisa. Let's go answer the rest of the question.
Mr. Himura is angry, I know, because it's all the fault of the ocean.
It's not fair, but it's the right answer.
It's not fair! It's not wrong!
It's the ocean's fault, but it's not fair.
The sea is the same. No. Interesting.
Interesting!
Nimura was hungry and angry at the ocean for going on vacation.
The fight got heated.
What kind of worldview is this?
Are they dating? What's this?
I'm hungry.
Why are they going on vacation when I'm hungry?
Thank you for watching.
Now we have a general entertainment question for the MC.
As an entertainer, I'd like you to answer this one.
Kubo. Well, you do radio work.
Yes, I am an MC.
I do a lot of MC work.
Yes, I do.
Kubo's answer
Main character
Main character... MC, yes...
I'm not an MC?
Ikeda's answer
Main commentator.
I said commentator.
I thought it was right, but I looked it up and it's not.
Look it up. That's what you're reviewing.
I see.
That's not right. It's not right.
Yoda's answer.
Michael Jackson.
Not even close.
Where's Jackson?
Michael is MJ, right?
MJ.
I've been thinking about it a lot.
Michael Jackson.
I took that part. I took Jackson's part.
That's funny.
I don't know where to take it.
You know, great people become words.
But it's not Jackson.
It's not Jackson.
Now, here's the next question.
CD.
I don't know how anyone could miss this one.
Compact disc.
Compact?
Compact.
CD is a compact disc
Compact
Plum
We sell a lot of them, Captain.
What does it stand for?
What's on the carnival disc?
What's in the carnival disc?
I like it. It's a carnival disc.
So you're selling a carnival disc?
Yes, we do.
We are
We bring you carnivals.
This one does.
No, it's not.
Okuda, is this the worst answer?
It's the worst!
OkudaLet's go!
Copy disk!
A copy disk!
Is it a crime to sell them?
It's a crime.
You can't do this.
This is piracy.
It's piracy.
Are you selling copies?
You are not selling copies.
Copies.
Why are people's names so long?
Now, Tsutsui's answer
Cassette DVD
DVD
I got it on DVD!
Why did you mix old and new?
It's not a cassette!
It's a cassette with music.
Tsutsui is wrong, but it doesn't look wrong at all.
I can't get in!
It's like, "This is the right answer.
Right.
The last one.
The last?
Yes, ma'am.
Here you go.
This one says, "Complete the cactus by adding people.
By the way, this is Kaki and Ikeda's.
I knew it.
Okay.
This is how it's done, right?
This is fine, right?
You have to hold this knee or something.
Let's answer on the stomach.
Let's do the answer on the stomach.
Oh, wow.
He's holding his ankle.
I'm good at drawing on the stomach, but I can't do this.
I can't do this.
You can't do this, Inoue-san.
He's holding her ankle.
It's impossible unless you break it like this.
It's impossible to support a human being with just an ankle.
The guy on top... he's just trying to make you feel something.
He's already dying.
He's about to get another shot at a soul.
It's his soul!
Let's finish with Sakaguchi's cactus!
Oh, this is great!
Congratulations!
Wow! Money!
Wait a minute. I'm not drawing a cactus man.
So that's what you're doing. That's what you're doing.
I drew a cactus man.
I mean, anything with a cactus man is going to be cactus.
I'm scared. If I saw this guy at a field day, he'd be all over the news.
I drew a cactus man.
Now it's time to announce the worst ranking!
Who will be the fourth brain king?
We will start from the worst five.
Total score: 21 points
The worst 5 are
Okamoto
Blake
I thought I was going to win
I knew I was going to win.
Good for you. I heard a "huh" from Gossey.
I got a 6 in English and math.
I can do it.
But I didn't get a 4 in Common Sense.
I got a 4 in common sense.
That's good.
But I'm in 5th place.
Tomisato.
Tomisato is next in the worst four.
Sugawara follows, each by one point.
In the 5th term, there are smart kids and bad kids
I think overall, it's a good balance.
Yes, I think we have a good balance.
Let's start with number one.
Let's go for number one.
It's finally decided.
Let's see who has the brains.
Worst first place, with a total of six points.
Oh, no.
Six points.
And zero for Japanese and common sense.
Wow!
Zero in general knowledge and Japanese.
And now, I'd like to announce... the fourth annual competition's worst scorer.
Brains...
Yumiki!
Congratulations!
That's great!
Consecutive championships!
Amazing!
Second place goes to Nakamura.
Nakamura is also a past champion.
How about that!
Ikeda and Yumiki are separated by 77 points.
It's a nice group with a great range.
Me, my grandma who saw the broadcast last time,
Nao-chan, you went through so many things when you were a little girl,
She said that you had been through so many things when you were a little girl that all your memories from that time had slipped away.
Grandma!
What do you mean, "many things happened"?
I can't even face her.
But you know, it's great to be number one in everything.
Yes, it is.
Is it?
You're getting back on your feet fast.
Chance is Equal jacket photo completed.
Yamashita graduation concert, mobile selection started.
Hello, I'm Hina Okamoto.
I grew 2 cm taller in 2 months.
Please subscribe to my channel.
Bye bye.